Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to create a death system.
So if our player character loses all their hearts, we're going to make them die.
If we first go over to our Warrior animation folder and look for the death folder.
Once you're here, set all the images right click and go Sprite actions and create a Sprite.
Then if we set all the sprites and right click and go create flipbook and we can just call this warrior
death.
Next, if we go over to our player character folder and find the warrior animation source.
We want to create a new animation sequence and just call this death.
And under the animation data, look for the flipbook that we just made.
And go save.
We can close this and open up our Warrior Animation blueprint.
And head over to the new state machine.
And we just want to right click and create a job node and call this death.
Then we can just rack off here and look for animation state and we're going to call this die.
Lot to head inside here and look for the play death animation that we just made and connect this into
here.
Select the death animation and just uncheck loop animation because I don't want this animation to loop
once you play it.
We're not going to play it again.
Then we can go compile and save.
And if we head over to our player character.
Open up our player blueprint.
And go over to the event any damage node.
So after we damage our player character and play a screen check and then update our player HUD, we're
going to check to see if our player has more than zero health.
If they don't, then we're going to kill our player character.
So if we drag in our health and we want to check to see if this value is less than or equal to zero.
So just drag off here and look for Branch and hook up from completed into here.
If that is true, then we're going to kill our player.
And when we kill our player, we're going to disable that input.
So if you just right click and lock for disable input.
And then we right click and forget player, controller and hook this up to the player controller.
And this will just make it so our player character can't move in the game.
After we do this, we want to drag in our animation component and get the animation instance, and from
here we want to call the jump to load.
And I think we called it die.
So I call it death.
So here under Trump name, I'm going to type in death.
And we just want to hook up, just able input into here.
And then finally, just so that this doesn't repeat, if we're attacked again, when we have normal
health, we want to just drag up here and look forward to once.
Just going to move with these notes as it's a bit messy.
And now I can go compile and go play.
So let's say I let the scan turn damaged me or times I should die and then play my death animation.
Okay.
Nice.
So I died and I place the death animation.